Guide to the Reston Black Focus records, 1960-2005
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Reston Black Focus records
1960-2005
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Edward G. Sharp
C0137
2.75 linear feet (6 boxes)
The collection consists of papers from the Reston Black Focus, such as correspondence, advertisements, financial information and general information. Also included in the collection is a series on the Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) with papers and other information from the Association.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Edward G. Sharp on December 16, 2008.
Historical Information
Reston is a planned community in Northern Virginia. Robert E. Simon, Jr., the founder of Reston, purchased the land with the proceeds from the sale of Carnegie Hall in New York City in 1961. Construction began in 1963 with the building of Lake Anne. During the late 1960s and early 1970s, the Reston Black Focus was established. The Reston Black Focus was created to encourage black citizens to participate more in Reston and to promote black culture and lifestyles.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of papers from the Reston Black Focus, such as correspondence, advertisements, financial information and general information. Also included in the collection is a series on the Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) with papers and other information from the Association.
Series one is titled correspondence. The series has correspondence to and from the Reston Black Focus. The correspondence is from a variety of people such as Beverley Sharp, Edward Sharp and others. Also included in the collection are emails dated later than most of the series. The series contained in boxes 1 through 2 and is dated from 1967 to 2005.
Series two is titled By-laws. The series is a collection of various By-laws from the Reston Black Focus. The By-laws are in draft and final form. Also included are Environmental Management Committee Charter, Fairfax County-Wide Black Citizens Association (BCA) and other committees. The series is contained in box 2 only and is dated from 1968 to 1974.
Series three is titled committee. The series contains paperwork from different committees. Included are reports, Board of Directors meeting, election results, meeting minutes and other papers from committees. The series is contained in boxes 2 through 3 and is dated from 1969 to 1975.
Series four is titled finance. The series has information relating to the finances of the Reston Black Focus. The papers include calculations, financial reports, budgets and other financial documents. The series is contained in box 3 only and is dated from 1970 to 1975.
Series five is titled publications. This contains mostly booklets, brochures and other information from Reston and the Reston Black Focus. Some of the information includes The Reston Philosophers, Directory and United Virginia Bank. The series is contained in boxes 3 through 4 and is dated 1965 to 2000.
Series six is titled newsclippings. The newsclippings are articles written about Reston and the Reston Black Focus. Included are articles from the Reston Times and the Washington Post. The series is contained in boxes 4 through 5 and is dated from 1960 to 2005.
Series seven is titled Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA). The series contains general information on the Reston Homeowners Association such as deed of dedications, meetings, election results and others. The series is contained in box 5 only and is dated from 1960 to 1972.
Series eight is titled General Information. This series contains a variety of papers relating to Reston Black Focus. Included are maps, biographies, schedule of events and general notes. The series is contained in boxes 5 through 6 and is dated from 1960 to 2005.
Arrangement
Organized into eight series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1967-2005 (Box 1-2)
Series 2: By-Laws, 1968-1974 (Box 2)
Series 3: Committee, 1969-1975 (Box 2-3)
Series 4: Finance, 1970-1975 (Box 3)
Series 5: Publications, 1965-2000 (Box 3-4)
Series 6: Newsclippings, 1960-2005 (Box 4-5)
Series 7: Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA), 1960-1972 (Box 5)
Series 8: General Information, 1960-2005 (Box 5-6)
Related Material
The Special Collections and Archives also holds the Planned Community Archives and other personal papers and organizational records that document Reston, Virginia, and other planned communities.
Alternative Form Available
The entire collection is digtized and availalbe through the Reston Black Focus collection.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Reston Association.
Reston Black Focus.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
African Americans--Virginia--Reston.; Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1967-2005; (1.5 boxes)
  The correspondence is from a variety of people such as Beverley Sharp, Edward Sharp and others. Also included in the collection are emails dated later than most of the series.
  - Announcement, August 31, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, July 9, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Contract, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Election, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Election Information, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Email: Subject-Aunt Jessie's Obituary, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Email: Subject-Re: Aunt Jessie's Obituary, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Expenses-Christmas Party, February 25, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Festival, July 30, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Festival Committee, June 11, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - From: Alicia Ashaw, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - From: Beverley D. Sharp, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - From: Beverley D. Sharp, September 19, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - From: Edward Sharp (2 letters), April 14, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - From: Frederick A. Fresh, August 7, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - From: James R. Thomas, August 29, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Internal Revenue Service (IRS), June 25, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lakeview Apartment Project, May 28, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - List of Addresses, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mailed Membership Questionnaire, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Membership Meeting, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Memorandum, January 6, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Memorandum, May 15, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Memorandums, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Message to Block Representatives, September 27, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Newsletter, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Newsletter, November 22, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Newsletter, June 25, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Newsletter, July 18, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Newsletter, August 19, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Newsletter, October 23, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Newsletter, November 22, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Newsletter, January 29, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Newsletter, February 21, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Newsletter, March 27, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Newsletter, April 21, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Newsletter, July 2, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Newsletter, January 22, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Newsletter, April 30, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Newsletter-Graduates, June 22, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - New Release, July 18, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - New Release, July 18, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Note, 1970s (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Open Letter to Members Reston Second Homeowners Association, April 24, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Play Description, 1960s (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Questionnaire, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Release, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Reston Black Focus Goals, April 25, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Reston Second Homeowners Association, October 27, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Roles and Responsibility, August 24, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Theater Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - To: Arthur G. Hawkins, September 23, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - To: Angela Terrell, August 6, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, August 14, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - To: Beverley D. Sharp, November 5, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, December 10, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, Ms., December 11, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, Mrs., December 28, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, June 18, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - To: Beverley Sharp, November 12, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - To: Black Focus Arts Festival, August 8, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - To: Black Arts Festival, August 12, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - To: Black Arts Festival, August 15, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - To Block Representatives, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - To Block Representatives, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - To Block Representatives, June 2, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - To Block Representatives, August 30, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - To: Board of Directors, December 9, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - To: Captain Greer, August 18, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - To: Committee Member, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - To: Daniel Turner, April 24, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - To: Dennis J. Fischer, May 21, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - To: Douglas Kleine, January 11, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - To: Editor, Reston Times, August 26, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - To: Edward G. Sharp, November 14, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - To: Edward Sharp, April 6, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Letter from Gene Bergoffen, Robert Pierce, and Michael Healy of the Reston Community Association to Edward Sharp., April 17, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - To: Edward Sharp, March 25, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - To: Edward Sharp, December 14, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - To: Ernestine Bush, December 28, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - To: Focus Member, April 5, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - To: Frederick Fresh and Steering Committee, September 8, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - To: Frederick A. Fresh, February 6, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - To: Frederick S. Humphries, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - To: Frederick S. Humphries, Ph.D, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - To: Frederick Humphries, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - To: Frederick S. Humphries, August 28, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - To: Frederick Naef, June 14, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - To: Glen Saunders, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - To: Glenn W. Saunders Jr., September 10, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - To: Glenn Saunders, March 5, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - To: Glenn Saunders, August 18, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - [From] George Mason University (GMU), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - To: Hendrick K. Sijgers, July 14, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - To: Howard Robinson, July 29, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - To: Institute for Services to Education, Incorporated, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - To: James F. Leonard, President of United Nations Association, March 25, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - To: John L. Spitler, January 27, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - To: John L. Spitler, January 27, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - To: Members of Second Homeowners Association (SHOA), March 2, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - To: Mona Blake, August 21, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - To: Norman Seabrooks, September 20, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - To: Reston Times, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - To: Reston Times, Editor, June 26, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - To: Robert F. Horan, September 19, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - To: Royce Hanson, December 12, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - To: Royce Hanson, February 2, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - To: Steering Committee, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - To: Town Council Members, January 11, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - To: Town Crier Editorial Board, May, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - To: Van Tile Whitfield, June 16, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - To: William Magness, April 15, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - To: William Magness, May 31, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Department of Taxation, October 1, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series 2: By-Laws, 1968-1974; (16 folders)
  The series is a collection of various By-laws from the Reston Black Focus. The By-laws are in draft and final form. Also included is Environmental Management Committee Charter and other committees.
  - By-Laws of Reston Black Focus, Incorporated, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - By-Laws of Reston Black Focus, Incorporated (draft), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - By-Laws of Reston Black Focus, Incorporated, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Charter Adopted, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Charter (Draft Revised), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Charter (Draft-Revised), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Draft Charter, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Draft Charter, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Draft Charter, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Draft Charter, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Environmental Management Committee Charter, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Fairfax County-Wide Black Citizens Association (BCA), 1970s (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Human Rights Ordinance, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Outline of Education Committee, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rules and Regulations Governing the Use of Tennis Court, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - "What?, Why?, How?", 1970s (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Series 3: Committee, 1969-1975; (0.5 box)
  Included in the series are reports, Board of Directors meeting, election results, meeting minutes and other papers from committees.
  - Agenda, February 26, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Agenda, January 26, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Agenda (Notes), July 30, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Annual Reports, November 13, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Annual Report, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Biographical Sketch, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Black College Choir Concert, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, September 18, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, October 10, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Board of Directors, December, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, December 12, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Bridge Club Membership List, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Calendar of Events, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Committee Reports, February 12, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Conference, May 6, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Conference Agenda, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Conference Committee Report, August 26, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Department of Consumer Affairs, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Election Report, December 9, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Election, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Festival, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - General Membership Meeting, November 1, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Human Rights Commission, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - June Happenings, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - List of Board of Directors, Feburary 13, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Meeting Minutes, June 30, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Meeting Minutes, June 24, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Membership Directory, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Membership List, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Memorandum, August 5, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Newsletter, February 14, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Newsletter, April 13, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Newsletter, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Newsletter, March 7, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Newsletter, April 13, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Newsletter, October 16, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Newsletter, January 14, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Newsletter, April 30, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Notes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Official Ballot, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Official Ballot, July 30, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Program, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Report, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Report and Agenda, July 30, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Schedule, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Schedule of Events, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Second Seminar in Race Relations Problems Solving, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Statement of Candidacy-Beverley D. Sharp, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Steering Committee Meetings, January 3, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, January 10, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, January 10, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, June 1, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, June 10, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, June 24, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, July 16, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Steering Committee Meeting Attachment no. 1, July 16, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Steering Committee Members List, August 6, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Steering Committee Meeting, August 12, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Steering Committee Members List, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Supper Club/Discussion Group, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Series 4: Finance, 1970-1975; (0.5 box)
  The series has information relating to the finances of the Reston Black Focus. The papers include calculations, budgets and other financial documents.
  - Agreements, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Application for Recognition of Exemption, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Budget, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Budget, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Calculations, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Calculations, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Calculations, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Calculations, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Calculations, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Cash Request and Fiscal Report Form, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Delivery Receipts, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - District of Columbia (DC) Federation of Musicians, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Expansion Arts Summer Projects Grants Announced, July 23, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Festival Account, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Festival Financial Summary, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Financial Report, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Financial Report, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Financial Statement, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Financial Summary of 1974, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - General Grant Provisions, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Invoice, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (3 copies), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Notes, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Notes, September 11, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Orders, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Order Forms, July 31, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Order Forms, July 1, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Payments, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Price List, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Project Budget, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Proposal for a Black Arts Festival, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Receipts, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Receipts, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Receipts, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Receipts, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Reservation, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Statement of Receipts and Expenditures, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Tax Forms, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - The United Negro College Fund, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Series 5: Publications, 1965-2000; (1 box)
  This contains mostly brochures and other information from Reston and the Reston Black Focus. Some of the information includes The Reston Philosophers, Directory and United Virginia Bank.
  - A Proposed Form of Inner Government for the New Town of Reston, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Amanda Galloway Aid Society, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Article-"Democracy in the New Towns", 1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "By Invitation Only" by Ginnie Gross (2 photos), 1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Brochure-Lake Anne Nursery-Kindergarten, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Brochure-New Town Agenda, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Brochure-Reston: Smith Townhouses, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brochure-The Reston Philosophers, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bulk Mail, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Directory (2 copies), 1973 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Festival, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Flyer-Gala, December 27, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Flyer-The Hair Company, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Notices for Warner Cable TV Advertising Wheel, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Open Models, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Program-"A Tale of Two Toms", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Programs-Black Arts Festival, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Purposes and Activities (2 copies), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - The Reston Letter, May 21, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Restonian Magazine, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The Reston Philosophers, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - United Virginia Bank, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series 6: Newsclippings, 1960-2005; (1 box)
  The newsclippings are articles written about Reston and the Reston Black Focus. Included are articles from the Reston Times and the Washington Post.
  - "A Festival of Black Arts", August 25, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - "Black Culture", 1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - "Dance, Tour, Highlight Reston Festival" (2 copies), August 16, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - "Focus on Black Culture", September 1, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - "Human Rights.." (6 articles, 3 copies), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Human Rights (6 articles), 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - "List of Those Honored", 1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - New Town (6 articles), September 12, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "New Town Gaps Discerned at Seminar", September 12, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - "Racial Incident", 1960s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Reston Times (4 articles), July 13, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Reston Times and Globe (2 copies), August 16, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Reston Times: "Black Arts Tennis Tourney Set", August 29, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Reston Times: "Building Ban Appeal Certain", August 22, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Reston Times: "Court Strike County..", August 15, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Reston Times: "Festival: Bonds Not Forgotten", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Reston Times: "6th Annual Black Arts Festival Nears", August 29, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Reston Times: "What's Inside", 1976 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Seminar (2 Articles), August 8, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - "Spotlight On: Black Focus", August 27, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Steering Committee Meeting (2 articles), July 4, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - "The 'Real Life' Takes Over..", July 20, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - The Reston Times, September 4, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - The Reston Times, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - The Washington Post (4 articles), July 20, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - The Washington Post (2 articles), September 1, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Washington Post (4 photos), 1970s (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - The Washington Post: "Father, Daughter, Roger Over", August 5, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Trouble Erupts At Herndon High", 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Series 7: Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA), 1960-1972; (12 folders)
  The series contains general information on the Reston Homeowners Association such as deed of dedications, meetings, election results and others.
  - Blank Query Report, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Deed of Dedication, March 31, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Directory of Reston Organizations, May 19, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Elections Final Report, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Members List, March 22 and October 10, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Recommendation for a Consolidated Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA), 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Report to the Members of the Second Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) Election Committee Report (6 copies), September 7, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) Record, April-July, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Section V-Problems and Opportunities, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Study of the Organization and Services, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Study of the Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) by Booze-Allen and Hamilton, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Series 8: General Information, 1960-2005; (1.5 boxes)
  This series contains a variety of papers relating to Reston Black Focus. Included are maps, biographies, schedule of events and general notes.
  - A Reston Festival, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Action, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Addresses, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Addresses, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 20)